Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Miss
يفتقد
It's time to pay respects.
حان الوقت لتقديم الاحترام.
Sir
سيد
It's time for court.
لقد حان وقت المحكمة.
Your Majesty has issued a decree.
لقد أصدر جلالتكم مرسوما.
Grand Secretary Rui Yu is specially granted
تم منح السكرتير الأكبر روي يو بشكل خاص
to marry General Nan's daughter, Nan Chenxiao.
للزواج من ابنة الجنرال نان، نان تشينشياو.
The wedding will be held on an auspicious day.
سيتم عقد حفل الزفاف في يوم ميمون.
A wedding, a wedding!
حفل زفاف، حفل زفاف!
I heard Grand Secretary Rui Yu
سمعت السكرتير الأعظم روي يو
is dignified and graceful.
هي كريمة ورشيقة.
Hasn't married for so many years.
لم يتزوج منذ سنوات عديدة.
Doesn't even have a bedding maid.
لا يوجد حتى خادمة الفراش.
Yes, I heard that too.
نعم سمعت ذلك أيضًا.
This General's Tiger Daughter, Nan Chenxiao,
ابنة النمر لهذا الجنرال، نان تشينشياو،
is said to be big and fierce-looking.
يقال أنه كبير الحجم وذو مظهر شرس.
And has a terrible temper.
ولديه مزاج رهيب.
Your Majesty wants Sir to marry a Tiger Daughter.
جلالتك تريد من سيدي أن يتزوج من ابنة النمر.
Isn't that asking for trouble?
أليس هذا طلبًا للمتاعب؟
But...
لكن...
She's a woman.
إنها امرأة.
Sir Rui, please.
سيدي روي، من فضلك.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحياتي جلالتك.
The Nan family has served loyally for generations.
لقد خدمت عائلة نان بإخلاص لأجيال.
So many heroes died on the battlefield.
لقد مات العديد من الأبطال في ساحة المعركة.
I
أنا
do not wish to wrong the Nan family.
لا أريد أن أخطئ في حق عائلة نان.
Your Majesty's action
عمل جلالتك
is truly wronging the Nan family.
إنه حقًا ظلم لعائلة نان.
Court politics are unpredictable.
السياسة في المحكمة غير قابلة للتنبؤ.
You should know the civil-military situation.
ينبغي عليك معرفة الوضع المدني والعسكري.
You've been my companion for fifteen years.
لقد كنت رفيقي لمدة خمسة عشر عامًا.
I hope
آمل
there will be many more fifteen years.
سيكون هناك خمسة عشر عامًا أخرى.
Your humble servant
خادمك المتواضع
will not disappoint Your Majesty.
لن يخيب ظن جلالتك.
Good, good, good.
جيد، جيد، جيد.
The previous dynasty had a Champion Marquis.
كانت السلالة السابقة لديها بطل ماركيز.
He joined the army young.
انضم إلى الجيش في شبابه.
After surviving the Three Kingdoms' wars,
بعد النجاة من حروب الممالك الثلاث،
the previous emperor named him Ever-Victorious General.
أطلق عليه الإمبراطور السابق لقب الجنرال المنتصر الدائم.
Young Master
السيد الشاب
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
There's trouble at home.
هناك مشكلة في المنزل.
Is it my mother's illness?
هل هو مرض أمي؟
Not Madam.
ليس سيدتي.
It's you.
إنه أنت.
You've been granted a marriage.
لقد تم منحك الزواج.
You scared me.
لقد اخافتني.
I thought it was something serious.
اعتقدت أنه كان شيئا خطيرا.
A royal marriage?
زواج ملكي؟
Come with me, quickly.
تعال معي بسرعة.
The eunuch with the decree is almost here.
إن الخصي الذي يحمل المرسوم قد وصل تقريباً.
Hurry!
عجل!
Let's go!
دعنا نذهب!
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Hurry!
عجل!
This...
هذا...
You haven't explained it yet.
لم تشرح ذلك بعد
How did it become a royal marriage?
كيف أصبح زواجًا ملكيًا؟
There's no time.
ليس هناك وقت.
After the wedding and wedding night,
بعد الزفاف وليلة الزفاف،
I'll find time to explain it all.
سأجد الوقت لشرح كل ذلك.
Your Majesty commands
جلالتك تأمر
Grand Secretary Rui Yu of Hanlin Academy is virtuous.
السكرتير الأكبر روي يو من أكاديمية هانلين هو شخص فاضل.
Filial and exemplary.
ابني ومثالي.
I am pleased with his work.
أنا مسرور بعمله.
Now, General Wei Bei's daughter, Nan Chenxiao,
الآن، ابنة الجنرال وي باي، نان تشينشياو
is respectful, graceful, and wise.
محترم، رشيق، وحكيم.
She is a perfect match for the Grand Secretary.
إنها مباراة مثالية لمنصب السكرتير الأعظم.
To fulfill this beautiful union,
لتحقيق هذا الاتحاد الجميل،
and balance civil and military harmony,
وتحقيق التوازن بين الانسجام المدني والعسكري،
I hereby arrange their marriage.
أنا أرتب زواجهما بموجب هذا.
They will wed on an auspicious day.
وسوف يتزوجان في يوم ميمون.
By imperial decree.
بموجب مرسوم إمبراطوري.
General Nan
الجنرال نان
This is a marriage granted by Your Majesty.
هذا الزواج الممنوح من جلالتكم.
Or do you mean
أم تقصد؟
you want to defy the decree?
هل تريد أن تتحدى المرسوم؟
This decree...
هذا المرسوم...
She really is a Tiger Daughter.
إنها حقا ابنة النمر.
Isn't this nonsense?
أليس هذا هراء؟
See?
يرى؟
I said it was nonsense.
قلت أنها هراء.
You dare say that?
هل تجرؤ على قول ذلك؟
No,
لا،
I just said one thing.
لقد قلت شيئا واحدا فقط.
Father
أب
The imperial command
الأمر الإمبراطوري
cannot be defied.
لا يمكن تحديها.
With the Rui family's status,
مع مكانة عائلة روي،
even a royal order
حتى أمر ملكي
can be negotiated.
يمكن التفاوض عليها.
You're just a fourth-rank official.
أنت مجرد مسؤول من الدرجة الرابعة.
Who can you negotiate with?
من يمكنك التفاوض معه؟
I trust Your Majesty has his reasons.
آمل أن يكون جلالتكم لديه أسبابه.
He won't harm me.
لن يؤذيني.
Nor the Rui family.
ولا عائلة روي.
What about your identity?
ماذا عن هويتك؟
Honestly,
بصدق،
just now,
الآن،
I thought it over.
لقد فكرت في الأمر.
We don't need to
نحن لا نحتاج الى ذلك
be overly anxious.
كن قلقًا للغاية.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
Either way,
في كلتا الحالتين،
we're the groom's side.
نحن من جانب العريس.
Right?
يمين؟
As long as we don't do
طالما أننا لا نفعل ذلك
that thing,
هذا الشيء
no one will ever know.
لا أحد سوف يعرف أبدًا.
Besides,
بجانب،
Yu'er
يوير
has always appeared frail.
لقد ظهر دائمًا ضعيفًا.
That's true,
هذا صحيح
but what if something happens?
ولكن ماذا لو حدث شيء؟
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
She is a Tiger Daughter, after all.
إنها ابنة النمر، بعد كل شيء.
What if the hungry tiger pounces?
ماذا لو انقض النمر الجائع؟
You rascal!
أيها الوغد!
Why don't you learn something decent?
لماذا لا تتعلم شيئا لائقا؟
I'm leaving.
انا ذاهب.
How do you treat your sister?
كيف تتعامل مع أختك؟
Why are you in such a hurry?
لماذا أنت في عجلة من أمرك؟
I'm in a hurry to disappear.
أنا في عجلة من أمري للاختفاء.
Don't want to anger my father to death.
لا أريد أن أغضب والدي حتى الموت.
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
I'm done talking, wife, I'm leaving.
لقد انتهيت من الحديث يا زوجتي، سأرحل.
Father
أب
Can you stop leaving?
هل يمكنك التوقف عن المغادرة؟
You're making me dizzy.
أنت تجعلني أشعر بالدوار.
How can I not be anxious?
كيف لا أشعر بالقلق؟
About this marriage,
وعن هذا الزواج،
do you have no thoughts?
هل ليس لديك أفكار؟
Isn't it on an auspicious day?
أليس في يوم مبارك؟
The date isn't set yet.
لم يتم تحديد التاريخ بعد.
There's still time.
مازال هناك وقت .
Once the date is set, it'll be too late.
بمجرد تحديد التاريخ، سيكون الأوان قد فات.
The scholar-officials hold sway.
العلماء-المسؤولون هم الذين يسيطرون.
Rui Yu leads the Hanlin Purists.
روي يو يقود جماعة هانلين بوريستس.
If our family appeals to Your Majesty,
إذا استأنفت عائلتنا جلالتك،
to revoke the decree,
لإلغاء المرسوم،
wouldn't that disgrace the Rui family?
ألا يعتبر هذا عارًا لعائلة روي؟
Besides, in court,
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، في المحكمة،
things would get even harder.
الأمور ستصبح أصعب.
So we just wait here, doing nothing?
إذن نحن فقط ننتظر هنا، ولا نفعل شيئًا؟
Wait until you marry over there,
انتظر حتى تتزوج هناك،
and your identity is exposed,
ويتم الكشف عن هويتك،
and our whole Nan family is executed?
وعائلتنا نان بأكملها تم إعدامها؟
Father,
أب،
can you let me have some peace?
هل يمكنك أن تسمح لي بالحصول على بعض السلام؟
Let me think this through, please?
دعني أفكر في هذا الأمر من فضلك؟
Father,
أب،
if Rui Yu despises me
إذا كان روي يو يحتقرني
and calls off the marriage,
ويلغى الزواج
Fu Lü, Fu Lü!
فو لو، فو لو!
What are you carrying?
ماذا تحمل؟
Madam said it's for making the wedding dress.
قالت السيدة أنها لصنع فستان الزفاف.
Your mother's illness has worsened.
لقد تفاقم مرض والدتك.
Mother used to
كانت أمي تستخدم
recognize me as her youngest son.
تعرفت عليّ باعتباري ابنها الأصغر.
Now she completely thinks I'm a girl.
الآن هي تعتقد تماما أنني فتاة.
Put that over there.
ضع ذلك هناك.
Help me with something.
ساعدني في شيء ما.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
This...
هذا...
Just go ahead and do it.
فقط اذهب وافعل ذلك.
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
I'm off.
انا ذاهب.
Son,
ابن،
do you have a plan?
هل لديك خطة؟
Father,
أب،
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll step right on those scholar-officials' tails.
سأخطو مباشرة على ذيول هؤلاء المسؤولين الأكاديميين.
If it doesn't blow up,
إذا لم ينفجر،
I'll make sure it does.
سأتأكد من ذلك.
Come out and pay your debt!
تعال وسدد دينك!
Pay up! Pay up! Pay up!
ادفع! ادفع! ادفع!
Nan Chenxiao took a hairpin from my shop.
أخذت نان تشينشياو دبوس شعر من متجري.
Picked a bolt of red silk from my shop.
التقطت قطعة من الحرير الأحمر من متجري.
Fifteen taels of silver in total.
خمسة عشر تايل من الفضة في المجموع.
Fifty taels.
خمسون تايل.
I also have a horse from the Western Regions.
لدي أيضًا حصان من المناطق الغربية.
Nan Chenxiao owes money.
نان تشينشياو مدين بالمال.
Go ask the Nan family for it.
اذهب واسأل عائلة نان عن ذلك.
Why block the Rui family’s gate?
لماذا حجب بوابة عائلة روي؟
She said
قالت
she'll be Rui family's daughter-in-law.
ستكون زوجة ابن عائلة روي.
All her expenses are Rui family's responsibility.
جميع نفقاتها تقع على عاتق عائلة روي.
Father,
أب،
So brazen before the wedding!
وقحة جدًا قبل الزفاف!
How improper!
كم هو غير لائق!
Father,
أب،
Calm down.
اهدأ.
Take care of your health.
اعتني بصحتك
Bring me a brush.
احضر لي فرشاة.
I'm going to the palace to see His Majesty.
سأذهب إلى القصر لرؤية جلالته.
Father is heading out.
الأب متجه للخارج.
You’re back just in time.
لقد عدت في الوقت المناسب.
Deliver a memorial to the palace for me.
أرسل لي نصبًا تذكاريًا إلى القصر.
Submit a petition.
تقديم التماس.
Even if I risk my old face,
حتى لو خاطرت بوجهي القديم،
I must beg His Majesty
يجب أن أتوسل إلى جلالته
to revoke the decree.
لإلغاء المرسوم.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
This morning,
هذا الصباح،
your elder brother and I went out
لقد خرجنا أنا وأخوك الأكبر
to buy things for your wedding.
لشراء الأشياء لحفل الزفاف الخاص بك.
A crowd blocked our front gate.
قام حشد من الناس بإغلاق البوابة الأمامية لمنزلنا.
They said Nan Chenxiao bought things and owes money.
قالوا أن نان تشينشياو اشترى أشياء وعليه أموال.
They demanded our family pay.
لقد طالبوا بأجور عائلتنا.
That Miss Nan is too much.
إن الآنسة نان كثيرة جدًا.
Isn't she taking advantage of your good temper?
هل هي تستغل مزاجك الجيد؟
Father,
أب،
Your Majesty has reigned only a year.
لقد حكم جلالتكم لمدة عام واحد فقط.
This is his first imperial marriage decree.
وهذا هو أول مرسوم زواج إمبراطوري له.
If Rui family asks to revoke it,
إذا طلبت عائلة روي إلغاءه،
what will he think?
ماذا سيفكر؟
How hard will it be for him?
كم سيكون الأمر صعبا بالنسبة له؟
To fulfill His Majesty's will,
لتحقيق إرادة جلالته،
we can only do our best.
لا يمكننا إلا أن نبذل قصارى جهدنا.
Reporting to Your Majesty:
تقرير إلى جلالتكم:
Miss Nan
الآنسة نان
owes three taels of gold
يدين بثلاثة تايلات من الذهب
and three hundred taels of silver.
وثلاثمائة تايل من الفضة.
She told the merchants
قالت للتجار
to collect from the Rui family.
لجمعها من عائلة روي.
What did she buy?
ماذا اشترت؟
Jewelry, fabrics,
المجوهرات والأقمشة
antiques and curios.
التحف والأشياء الغريبة.
Yes.
نعم.
And also a
وأيضا
fine horse from the Western Regions.
حصان جميل من المناطق الغربية.
Looks like Nan Chenxiao
يبدو مثل نان تشينشياو
truly is a General's Tiger Daughter.
إنها حقا ابنة النمر للجنرال.
Even her steed is ready.
حتى جوادها جاهز.
Since that's the case,
وبما أن هذه هي الحالة،
go to Qin Tian Jian now.
اذهب إلى تشين تيان جيان الآن.
Set their wedding date.
حدد موعد زفافهم.
Pick the best day within ten days.
اختر أفضل يوم خلال عشرة أيام.
Yes.
نعم.
When the time comes,
عندما يحين الوقت،
act decisively.
التصرف بحزم.
Avoid further trouble.
تجنب المزيد من المتاعب.
Father, make your move!
أبي، تحرك!
Watch closely.
شاهد عن كثب.
Father,
أب،
Thank you for letting me win.
شكرا لك على السماح لي بالفوز.
How did it go?
كيف كان الأمر؟
Did the Rui family
هل عائلة روي
storm into the palace to beg for a divorce?
اقتحام القصر للتوسل للحصول على الطلاق؟
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
The Rui family paid off the debt.
سددت عائلة روي الدين.
They paid all that money?
دفعوا كل تلك الأموال؟
Not a single coin short.
لا يوجد عملة واحدة قصيرة.
This...
هذا...
Well, that's that.
حسنا، هذا هو الأمر.
They paid it all.
لقد دفعوا كل شيء.
Hurry, think of another way!
اسرع، فكر في طريقة أخرى!
If one plan fails,
إذا فشلت إحدى الخطط،
I have a second.
عندي ثانية.
Fu Lü!
فو لو!
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Where to?
إلى أين؟
To stir things up.
لتحريك الأمور.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Someone's coming!
شخص ما قادم!
Okay, go, go, go!
حسنًا، اذهب، اذهب، اذهب!
It's a woman.
إنها امرأة.
Wrong person.
الشخص الخطأ.
What do we do now?
ماذا نفعل الآن؟
We've circled around so many times.
لقد دارنا حول بعضنا البعض عدة مرات.
Everyone we meet is either a servant
كل شخص نلتقي به هو إما خادم
or an old man.
أو رجل عجوز.
Thought we'd succeed this time.
اعتقدنا أننا سننجح هذه المرة.
Why does the Rui manor have so many people?
لماذا يوجد في قصر روي هذا العدد الكبير من الناس؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Where now?
أين الآن؟
Sir.
سيد.
Lord Rui.
اللورد روي.
Eunuch Li.
الخصي لي.
You came so late.
لقد أتيت متأخرا جدا.
Does His Majesty urgently summon me?
هل جلالته يستدعيني بشكل عاجل؟
I'm here to deliver His Majesty's message.
أنا هنا لنقل رسالة جلالته.
Rui Yu, receive the imperial decree.
روي يو، تلقي المرسوم الإمبراطوري.
After Qin Tian Jian observed the stars,
بعد أن لاحظ تشين تيان جيان النجوم،
the auspicious date chosen is the ninth of September.
التاريخ الميمون الذي تم اختياره هو التاسع من شهر سبتمبر.
Grand Secretary Rui Yu is granted
تم منح السكرتير الأعظم روي يو
marriage to General Nan Hongyi's daughter,
الزواج من ابنة الجنرال نان هونغ يي،
Nan Chenxiao.
نان تشينشياو.
All wedding items will be provided by the palace.
سيتم توفير كافة مستلزمات الزفاف من قبل القصر.
By imperial order.
بأمر إمبراطوري.
It will be in just five days.
سيكون ذلك خلال خمسة أيام فقط.
Isn't this too rushed?
أليس هذا متسرعًا جدًا؟
Father.
أب.
Accept the decree first.
اقبل المرسوم أولا.
I accept the decree and thank Your Majesty.
أقبل المرسوم وأشكر جلالتكم.
Grand Secretary Rui, please wait.
السيد السكرتير الأعظم روي، الرجاء الانتظار.
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
هل تحاول أن تقتل نفسك؟
Go back to your residence.
عد إلى مسكنك.
Then where are you going?
ثم إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Just going out for a walk.
فقط الخروج للنزهة.
I'm feeling troubled.
أنا أشعر بالانزعاج.
Alright, alright.
حسناً حسناً.
The Previous Emperor
الإمبراطور السابق
rose to power relying on the Empress Dowager's family’s military.
صعد إلى السلطة معتمداً على جيش عائلة الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
But feared the generals would become too powerful.
لكن كان يخشى أن يصبح الجنرالات أقوياء للغاية.
Their achievements threatened the throne.
إنجازاتهم هددت العرش.
A secret imperial decree
مرسوم إمبراطوري سري
was issued to search.
تم إصداره للبحث.
The male heirs of several generals' families
الورثة الذكور لعائلات العديد من الجنرالات
were all exiled as slaves.
تم نفيهم جميعا كعبيد.
Stop!
قف!
Kneel!
اركع!
Bribing officials,
رشوة المسؤولين
disrupting the court,
تعطيل المحكمة،
multiple crimes compounded.
جرائم متعددة مركبة.
Exiled three thousand li to the southwest.
نفي ثلاثة آلاف لي إلى الجنوب الغربي.
Take them away.
خذهم بعيدا.
You scoundrel!
أيها الوغد!
My father petitioned voluntarily,
لقد تقدم والدي بطلب طوعي،
surrendered his military command.
استسلم لقيادته العسكرية.
The Previous Emperor showed mercy.
لقد أظهر الإمبراطور السابق الرحمة.
He allowed my elder brother to guard the border before his coming-of-age.
لقد سمح لأخي الأكبر بحراسة الحدود قبل بلوغه سن الرشد.
He cannot return to the capital without an edict.
ولا يمكنه العودة إلى العاصمة دون مرسوم.
I can only disguise myself as a woman to avoid disaster.
لا أستطيع أن أتنكر في صورة امرأة إلا لتجنب الكارثة.
No way to serve my country, only self-pity.
لا توجد طريقة لخدمة بلدي، فقط الشفقة على الذات.
There are ways to help in troubled times.
هناك طرق للمساعدة في الأوقات الصعبة.
But from whom can I seek them?
ولكن من أستطيع أن أبحث عنهم؟
May you have a harmonious union.
أتمنى لكم اتحادًا متناغمًا.
Congratulations!
مبروك!
May your hearts be forever joined.
أتمنى أن تظل قلوبكم متصلة إلى الأبد.
Congratulations, Grand Secretary Rui!
مبروك، السكرتير الأعظم روي!
The auspicious hour has arrived.
لقد حانت الساعة الميمونة.
First, bow to Heaven and Earth.
أولاً، انحني أمام السماء والأرض.
Honor the heavens.
احترم السماوات.
A match made by fate.
مباراة صنعها القدر.
Second, bow to Heaven and Earth.
ثانياً، انحني أمام السماء والأرض.
Honor your parents.
أكرم والديك.
Family bonds.
الروابط العائلية.
Love as vast as the Eastern Sea.
الحب واسع كالبحر الشرقي.
Husband and wife bow to each other.
الزوج والزوجة ينحنيان لبعضهما البعض.
Blessed for three lifetimes.
مبارك لثلاث حيوات.
A match blessed by Heaven.
مباراة مباركة من السماء.
Miss Nan.
السيدة نان.
Sorry for the trouble.
عذرا على الإزعاج.
The ceremony is complete.
تم الانتهاء من الحفل.
Alright, alright.
حسناً حسناً.
May you have a harmonious union.
أتمنى لكم اتحادًا متناغمًا.
IMPERIAL DECREE ARRIVES
وصول المرسوم الإمبراطوري
GRAND SECRETARY RUI'S WEDDING
حفل زفاف السكرتير الكبير روي
YOUR MAJESTY BESTOWS A JADE RUYI
جلالتك تمنح رويي اليشم
A PAIR OF NUPTIAL CUPS
زوج من أكواب الزواج
A GLASS BLOSSOM JEWEL BOX
صندوق مجوهرات زجاجي من الزهور
A WHITE JADE PENDANT
قلادة من اليشم الأبيض
BY IMPERIAL ORDER
بأمر إمبراطوري
I
أنا
accept the decree and thank Your Majesty.
تقبل المرسوم وأشكر جلالتكم.
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
This jade pendant
هذه القلادة من اليشم
Your Majesty instructed
لقد أصدر جلالتك تعليماته
it is specially bestowed to you.
لقد تم منحها لك خصيصا.
Why not
ولم لا
take this auspicious moment
اغتنم هذه اللحظة الميمونة
and wear it now?
وأرتديها الآن؟
It will add to the joy.
سيضيف إلى الفرح.
And not waste Your Majesty’s kindness.
ولا تضيعوا لطف جلالتكم.
A good match.
مباراة جيدة.
Since you are here, Sir,
بما أنك هنا يا سيدي،
why not stay
لماذا لا تبقى
and have a cup of wedding wine before leaving?
وشرب كوب من نبيذ الزفاف قبل المغادرة؟
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Thank you, everyone.
شكرا للجميع.
Eat and drink well.
تناول الطعام والشراب جيدا.
Drink up, drink up!
اشرب، اشرب!
Let your elder brother teach you.
دع أخاك الأكبر يعلمك.
Drink a bit more later.
اشرب المزيد لاحقا.
As long as the groom drinks enough,
طالما أن العريس يشرب ما يكفي،
the wedding night won't be consummated.
لن تتم ليلة الزفاف.
Why is that?
لماذا هذا؟
Why do you ask so much?
لماذا تسأل كثيرا؟
Would your elder brother harm you?
هل يمكن لأخيك الأكبر أن يؤذيك؟
The groom is here!
العريس هنا!
Colleagues,
زملاء،
today I am getting married.
اليوم سأتزوج.
Thank you all for coming.
شكرا لكم جميعا على حضوركم.
Let me offer you all a toast.
اسمحوا لي أن أقدم لكم جميعا نخبًا.
Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
هتاف! هتاف! هتاف!
Come, come, come.
كيف، كيف، كيف.
Let me toast you all again.
اسمحوا لي أن أهنئكم جميعًا مرة أخرى.
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
You've already had several drinks.
لقد شربت عدة مشروبات بالفعل.
Tonight is such an important day.
إن الليلة هي يوم مهم جدًا.
If you drink too much,
إذا شربت كثيرا،
it's not good.
إنه ليس جيدا.
What's so bad about that?
ما هو السيء في ذلك؟
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
Don't miss your wedding night tonight!
لا تفوت ليلة زفافك الليلة!
That's right, that's right!
هذا صحيح، هذا صحيح!
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
No need to be so formal.
لا داعي لأن تكون رسميًا جدًا.
Tonight is such an important day.
إن الليلة هي يوم مهم جدًا.
We all understand.
نحن جميعا نفهم.
We won't make things hard for you.
لن نجعل الأمور صعبة عليك.
Right?
يمين؟
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
I...
أنا...
Alright, that's enough.
حسنا، هذا يكفي.
Let's go, let's go!
دعنا نذهب، دعنا نذهب!
Go, go, go.
إذهب! إذهب! إذهب.
Elder brother.
الاخ الاكبر.
Elder Brother Rui.
الأخ الأكبر روي.
We should have a drink together.
ينبغي لنا أن نشرب معًا.
Yes, yes, we should drink together.
نعم، نعم، ينبغي لنا أن نشرب معًا.
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
You shouldn't stay here.
لا ينبغي عليك البقاء هنا.
Tonight is your wedding night.
الليلة هي ليلة زفافك.
Don't keep your beautiful bride waiting.
لا تترك عروستك الجميلة تنتظر.
I...
أنا...
Go quickly!
اذهب بسرعة!
Go on!
إستمر!
Grand Secretary Rui.
السكرتير الأعظم روي.
Good luck!
حظ سعيد!
My lady.
سيدتي.
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
Is he going to...
هل هو ذاهب إلى...؟
My lady
سيدتي
You really are quite good-looking
أنت حقا وسيم جدا
What are you trying to do?
ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟
Don't be shy, my lady
لا تخجل يا سيدتي
No
لا
You scared me to death
لقد اخافتني حتى الموت
As long as I drink enough
طالما أنني أشرب ما يكفي
I won't have to consummate the marriage
لن أضطر إلى إتمام الزواج
Why isn't she here yet?
لماذا هي ليست هنا بعد؟
Are you hungry?
هل أنت جائع؟
Do you want
هل تريد
me to get you something to eat?
أريد أن أحضر لك شيئا لتأكله؟
You still have the mood to eat?
هل لا زال لديك الرغبة في الأكل؟
Grand Secretary Rui hasn't lifted my veil yet
لم يرفع السكرتير الأعظم روي حجابي بعد
How can I eat like this?
كيف يمكنني أن آكل هكذا؟
Right
يمين
Hurry up, Grand Secretary
اسرع يا سيدي السكرتير الأعظم
Then next, we should
ثم بعد ذلك، ينبغي لنا
Of course, drink the nuptial wine
بالطبع اشرب نبيذ الزفاف
From now on
من الآن فصاعدا
Please bear with me, my lady
من فضلك تحمليني سيدتي
Sorry, I...
عذرا، أنا...
Cheers
هتافات
Why isn't she reacting?
لماذا لا تتفاعل؟
How about
ماذا عن
we have another drink?
لدينا مشروب آخر؟
Okay
تمام
You think you can outdrink me?
هل تعتقد أنك تستطيع أن تتفوق علي في الشرب؟
She should be down now
ينبغي لها أن تكون في الأسفل الآن
Still not down
لم ينزل بعد
Why isn't she drunk yet?
لماذا لم تسكر بعد؟
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Darn it, darn it, darn it
اللعنة، اللعنة، اللعنة
Looks like I underestimated Rui Yu
يبدو أنني قللت من تقدير روي يو
If you won't fall
إذا لم تسقط
then I will
ثم سأفعل
Why did she fall?
لماذا سقطت؟
Such a low tolerance
مثل هذا التسامح المنخفض
Finally, she's down
أخيرا، لقد نزلت
Grand Secretary Rui
السكرتير الأعظم روي
Such a little weakling
مثل هذا الضعيف الصغير
I'm exhausted from today
أنا مرهق من اليوم
You act all scholarly
أنت تتصرف بشكل علمي
I'll beat you up
سأضربك
I'll pinch you
سأقرصك
She's not dead, is she?
إنها ليست ميتة، أليس كذلك؟
Why does she look small but feel so heavy?
لماذا تبدو صغيرة ولكنها تشعر بثقلها؟
What is she trying to do?
ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟
Is she going to change my clothes?
هل ستغير ملابسي؟
I'm not drunk
أنا لست في حالة سكر
This...
هذا...
Born of generals
مواليد الجنرالات
From a general's family
من عائلة جنرال
Carrying a weapon
حمل السلاح
Not hard to understand, right?
ليس من الصعب فهمه، أليس كذلك؟
Not hard to understand
ليس من الصعب فهمه
I'm really not drunk
أنا لست في حالة سكر حقا
Drunk people always think they're sober
يعتقد الأشخاص السكارى دائمًا أنهم رصينون
How about, Grand Secretary Rui
ماذا عن السكرتير الأعظم روي؟
you get some rest early
تحصل على بعض الراحة في وقت مبكر
Right
يمين
Everyone's tired
الجميع متعبون
Let's rest early
دعونا نرتاح مبكرا
I'll sleep on the couch
سأنام على الأريكة
Grand Secretary Rui is frail
السكرتير الأعظم روي ضعيف
Maybe I should sleep on the couch
ربما يجب أن أنام على الأريكة
How could I accept that?
كيف يمكنني أن أقبل ذلك؟
Stop fussing
توقف عن الضجة
It's settled
لقد تم تسويتها
I'll sleep on the couch
سأنام على الأريكة
Good night, Grand Secretary
تصبح على خير يا سيدي السكرتير الأعظم
Finally, everything's fine
أخيرا، كل شيء على ما يرام
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I'm Liang Jin
أنا ليانغ جين
Grand Secretary's personal maid
الخادمة الشخصية للسكرتير الأعظم
Here to bring sobering soup
هنا لتقديم حساء رصين
I'm Fu Lü
أنا فو لو
They might both be asleep
ربما يكون كلاهما نائمين
Why hang the warding charm?
لماذا تعليق تعويذة الحماية؟
What if they're not asleep?
ماذا لو لم يكونوا نائمين؟
Go check
اذهب للتحقق
You two
انتما الاثنان
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Eldest Young Madam
السيدة الشابة الأكبر سنا
I...
أنا...
I brought sobering soup for Grand Secretary
لقد أحضرت حساءً مهدئًا للأمين العام
Miss said she wanted food
قالت السيدة أنها تريد الطعام
I brought her something to eat
لقد أحضرت لها شيئا لتأكله
The candles are all out
الشموع كلها انطفأت
They must be settled
يجب تسويتها
Don't bring it
لا تحضرها
But Grand Secretary drank so much
لكن السكرتير الأعظم شرب كثيرًا
Won't she feel bad without sobering soup?
ألا تشعر بالسوء دون حساء مهدئ؟
Why bother with sobering soup?
لماذا نهتم بالحساء المهدئ؟
Drinking a lot is the point
شرب الكثير هو الهدف
Drinking makes things lively
الشرب يجعل الأشياء حيوية
That's true this time
هذا صحيح هذه المرة
Do I have to invite you two to leave?
هل يجب علي أن أدعوكما للمغادرة؟
Hurry
عجل
Go away
يبتعد
Yes, Eldest Young Madam
نعم، سيدتي الشابة الأكبر سنا
What if she tries something while I'm asleep?
ماذا لو حاولت فعل شيء ما وأنا نائم؟
I absolutely can't sleep
لا أستطيع النوم على الإطلاق
Sleeping with a pillow
النوم مع وسادة
Better than hugging me
أفضل من عناقي
Young Master
السيد الشاب
You...
أنت...
You're trying to scare me to death
أنت تحاول تخويفي حتى الموت
What time is it?
أي ساعة؟
It's the hour of Chen
لقد حان وقت تشين
Where's the little weakling?
أين الضعيف الصغير؟
She went to court
ذهبت إلى المحكمة
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Rui Yu, you're back.
روي يو، لقد عدت.
Sister-in-law, where are you headed?
أخت الزوجة، إلى أين أنت ذاهبة؟
I'm just about to call Miss Nan.
أنا على وشك الاتصال بالسيدة نان.
To teach her the rules for the tea ceremony.
لتعليمها قواعد حفل الشاي.
You came back at just the right time.
لقد عدت في الوقت المناسب.
Let's go together.
دعنا نذهب معا.
No need to trouble you, sister-in-law.
لا داعي لإزعاجك، أخت زوجي.
Were you both alright last night?
هل كنتما بخير الليلة الماضية؟
It was your first day of marriage.
لقد كان يومك الأول في الزواج.
She must've been nervous.
لا بد أنها كانت متوترة.
About the wedding night...
عن ليلة الزفاف...
Sister-in-law.
أخت الزوج أو اخت الزوجة.
Um...
واحد...
Is the return gift still not ready?
هل هدية العودة ليست جاهزة بعد؟
I prepared it long ago.
لقد قمت بإعداده منذ فترة طويلة.
Isn't the return gift due in a couple days?
هل يجب تسليم الهدية المرتجعة خلال يومين؟
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
Right now,
الآن،
the most important thing is you and the bride.
الأهم هو أنت والعروسة.
You two should make some plans soon.
ينبغي عليكما أن تضعا بعض الخطط قريبًا.
Elder Brother.
الأخ الأكبر.
Are you looking for sister-in-law for something?
هل تبحث عن أخت زوجتك لشيء ما؟
Ah, yes, yes.
أه، نعم، نعم.
Um, um...
اممممم...
Madam, where should I put my new purchase?
سيدتي، أين يجب أن أضع مشترياتي الجديدة؟
Just put it wherever you like.
فقط ضعه أينما تريد.
You're the most familiar with our courtyard.
أنت الأكثر دراية بفناءنا.
Find me a spot with sunlight,
أوجد لي مكانًا مشمسًا،
but not direct sun.
ولكن ليس أشعة الشمس المباشرة.
Spread out this wood to dry properly.
افردي هذا الخشب حتى يجف بشكل صحيح.
Why do you have so many darn requests?
لماذا لديك الكثير من الطلبات اللعينة؟
I haven't even gone to see Miss Nan yet.
ولم أذهب لرؤية الآنسة نان بعد.
Stop worrying about their business.
توقف عن القلق بشأن أعمالهم.
If you care, care about me instead.
إذا كنت تهتم، فاهتم بي بدلا من ذلك.
I ate breakfast, why am I hungry again?
لقد تناولت وجبة الإفطار، لماذا أشعر بالجوع مرة أخرى؟
Starve for all I care.
الموت جوعًا هو كل ما يهمني.
Go make me something tasty.
اذهب واصنع لي شيئًا لذيذًا.
Rui Yu.
روي يو.
Remember to call Miss Nan.
تذكر أن تتصل بالسيدة نان.
I'm starving.
أنا جائع.
I want a chicken leg.
أريد فخذ دجاجة.
I just ate three chicken legs and I'm hungry again.
لقد أكلت للتو ثلاث أرجل دجاج وأنا جائع مرة أخرى.
Eat three more, make it six.
تناول ثلاثة أخرى، لتصبح ستة.
I'm going to the study for some peace.
سأذهب للدراسة من أجل بعض السلام.
Go announce it in our courtyard.
اذهب وأعلن ذلك في ساحتنا.
When Miss Nan's time comes,
عندما يأتي وقت الآنسة نان،
she'll join me to greet Father in the main hall.
ستنضم إلي لتحية الأب في القاعة الرئيسية.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
Go on.
إستمر.
The room for books
غرفة الكتب
is bigger than our bedroom.
أكبر من غرفة نومنا.
Aren't scholar-officials supposed to be upright?
أليس من المفترض أن يكون المسؤولون الأكاديميون مستقيمين؟
Turns out they're this wealthy.
اتضح أنهم أغنياء إلى هذا الحد.
Found it.
وجدته.